now this one is special cuz it took us
20 years to create okay we started with
a kick drum like
this uh could you slow down that kick a
little more yeah more oh that's better
okay then we went about looking for a
high hat okay we started with
this uh but could you speed that up a
little bit more
more Okay cool so so far we had a kick
Trump we had a high hat
and after 5 minutes of producing we were
exhausted so we decided to go to lunch I
remember we were at lunch we ordered our
food and the waiter came back and he put
down the plate in a very interesting way
okay it sounded like this it sounded
cool and so we had the waiter do it
again and we recorded it this time like
this then we went about flamming the
sound now flamming a sound is when you
play the same sound over itself out of
time from itself I'll show you what I
mean
flam it more more now pitch it down an
octave okay we had our clap so so far we
had a pretty good Kick Drum we had a
good clap and we had a good high hat and
with those three drums we set about
trying to find a Groove okay we started
with this reg tone kind of thing like
[Music]
this but that didn't really feel like
AJR so we tried this doop thing
but we had done that before so we ended
up settling on this halftime trap sort
of beat like
this yeah yeah good start
okay next we wanted to find a piano line
and we wanted a piano line that felt
very emotional like
[Music]
this then we added some base like this
yeah that feels good Let It Ride for a
[Music]
sec okay that was a good start we had
the skeleton of the beat but after
working for a little while we sort of
got bored again which seems to be a
common theme in our work so we went to
the library I remember we were at the
library in our college and I was working
on my computer and Jack was watching old
home movies on his phone for reason are
you ready I'm
ready I don't know
don't put your heads closer together
[Music]
please and I remember I looked from my
work to jack on his phone and I just got
so annoyed that I blurred it out would
you put your phone down Jack looked at
me and he said say that again
so I said would you put your phone down
then we called up aretta and we said
could you play that on the
trumpet okay we had our trumpet Melody
the be was sounding pretty good so
far but we still wanted it to be more
emotional sounding and for that we use
violins
[Music]
finally in order to fill out the drums a
little more we added these tambourines
and high
[Music]
hats okay we were almost there it was
one more step we had a really solid
track but what we needed was a really
good Melody to go on top of that track
and as ja often does he sent me a voice
[Music]
memo but that wasn't catchy at all so he
sent me this
[Music]
one but that was less catchy than the
first one we we were kind of stuck here
we needed a melody and then we
remembered those old home movies Jack
was watching in the library
ABC
want put your
heads and do you remember at the start
of this story I told you it took 20
years to create this
song Here's why
bring all
[Music]
in I should move cuz New York is getting
money out there's LA but it's always
kind of sunny out and I don't want to no
more so I S my Baro
I'm okay I'm okay you say it but you
just don't mean it you're so insane
you're so insane shut up and just enjoy
this feeling don't you love it don't you
love it no I ain't
happy but
I'm don't you love it don't you love it
I ain't
happy
I hey he hey
hey hey hey hey hey hey but
I'm hey hey
hey but
[Music]
I'm well I can't fall asleep and I'm
losing my mind cuz it's 3 my brains on
fire I've been counting sheep but the
Sheep all died and I'm trying too hard
but I cannot try well I can't fall
asleep and I'm losing my mind cuz it's
three and my brains on fire I've been
can CH but the Sheep all died and I'm
not dead yet so tell me don't you love
it don't you love it no I ain't happy
yet but
I'm don't you love it don't you love it
no I ain't happy yet but I'm WI
I may be wrong I may be wrong it's
stupid but it's on the hand don't you
love it don't you love it I
happy but I'm
[Applause]